<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://persualia-plus.github.io/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://persualia-plus.github.io/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-10-07T18:27:07+00:00</updated><id>https://persualia-plus.github.io/en/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Persualia</title><subtitle>Agencia de marketing conversacional. Copy que conecta y resultados que se pueden medir.</subtitle><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">META VS. EUROPE: when politics turns into silence</title><link href="https://persualia-plus.github.io/en/news/marketing/ngo/2025/10/07/meta-vs-europe-when-policy-turns-to-silence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="META VS. EUROPE: when politics turns into silence" /><published>2025-10-07T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-07T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://persualia-plus.github.io/en/news/marketing/ngo/2025/10/07/meta-vs-europe-when-policy-turns-to-silence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://persualia-plus.github.io/en/news/marketing/ngo/2025/10/07/meta-vs-europe-when-policy-turns-to-silence/"><![CDATA[<p>This week Meta started blocking ads it labels as “political debate”. The move arrives after months of tension with the European Union over advertising transparency.</p>

<p>To dodge legal headaches, Meta chose the easiest firewall: <strong>ban every single ad that could be interpreted as opening a political debate</strong>. The result? Humanitarian, public health, education or social awareness campaigns are being thrown into the same basket. Campaigns exposing the genocide in Gaza, raising funds for global emergencies or pushing public health messages can now be blocked for being “political”.</p>

<p>It does not surprise me: <strong>transparency has never been Meta’s strong suit</strong>. Yet I am not shocked either that today’s political climate fuels the urge to control discourse via digital channels. <strong>Political debate has become uncomfortable for certain ideologies.</strong> When that happens, those in power tend to regulate, filter and simplify whatever they cannot control. This time, the silence does not only hit political parties —it mutes the voices that speak up for others. Foundations, NGOs and organisations trying to raise awareness or educate now see their ads tagged as “political” and automatically rejected.</p>

<p>At <strong>Persualia</strong> we know this territory well. For years, for different reasons, we have had to communicate social or political messages without using Meta’s disclaimer. <strong>It is frustrating and has caused more than one headache</strong>, but it has also forced us to find creative paths to keep meaningful messages alive.</p>

<h3 id="the-challenge-now-is-to-learn-how-to-communicate-differently">The challenge now is to learn how to communicate differently</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Move the most activist messages away from Meta, into owned channels or earned media where tone and freedom are not constrained.</li>
  <li>Inside Meta, focus the narrative on the human, empathetic side so the message is not flagged as a political debate.</li>
  <li>Craft content that sparks personal involvement —participation, reflection, small actions— without fuelling polarization.</li>
  <li>And above all, continue to talk about justice, rights and social causes with strategic and narrative intelligence.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Despite the obstacles, I remain optimistic:</strong> alternatives exist, there are new routes, and creativity is still the best tool to carry on.</p>

<p><strong>What do you think?</strong><br />
Do you believe this new Meta policy will end up shaping which social messages reach people?</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#socialadvertising</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#NGO</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#Meta</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#transparency</code> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#purposedrivencommunication</code></p>]]></content><author><name>Coral Costa</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="marketing" /><category term="ngo" /><category term="social-advertising" /><category term="NGO" /><category term="Meta" /><category term="transparency" /><category term="purpose-driven-communication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Meta started blocking ads it labels as “political debate”, after a long standoff with the European Union around advertising transparency.]]></summary></entry></feed>